<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>BBSRC Bistability of Cell Cycle Transitions Project</title>
    <link>http://cellcycle.org.uk/</link>
    <description>Recent content on BBSRC Bistability of Cell Cycle Transitions Project</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://cellcycle.org.uk/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>A single light-responsive sizer can control multiple-fission cycles in Chlamydomonas</title>
      <link>http://cellcycle.org.uk/publication/heldt_currbiol_2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cellcycle.org.uk/publication/heldt_currbiol_2019/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CDK1-CCNB1 creates a spindle checkpoint–permissive state by enabling MPS1 kinetochore localization</title>
      <link>http://cellcycle.org.uk/publication/hayward_jcb_2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cellcycle.org.uk/publication/hayward_jcb_2019/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MAD1-dependent recruitment of CDK1-CCNB1 to kinetochores promotes spindle checkpoint signaling</title>
      <link>http://cellcycle.org.uk/publication/alfonsoperez_jcb_2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cellcycle.org.uk/publication/alfonsoperez_jcb_2019/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two Interlinked Bistable Switches Govern Mitotic Control in Mammalian Cells</title>
      <link>http://cellcycle.org.uk/publication/rata_2018_currbiol/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cellcycle.org.uk/publication/rata_2018_currbiol/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dilution and titration of cell-cycle regulators may control cell size in budding yeast</title>
      <link>http://cellcycle.org.uk/publication/heldt_plos_2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cellcycle.org.uk/publication/heldt_plos_2018/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DNA Replication Determines Timing of Mitosis by Restricting CDK1 and PLK1 Activation</title>
      <link>http://cellcycle.org.uk/publication/hochegger_molcell_2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cellcycle.org.uk/publication/hochegger_molcell_2018/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Genome Stability during Cell Proliferation: A Systems Analysis of the Molecular Mechanisms Controlling Progression through the Eukaryotic Cell Cycle</title>
      <link>http://cellcycle.org.uk/publication/novak_curropinsysbiol_2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cellcycle.org.uk/publication/novak_curropinsysbiol_2018/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A comprehensive model for the proliferation-quiescence decision in response to endogenous DNA damage in human cells</title>
      <link>http://cellcycle.org.uk/publication/heldt_pnas_2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cellcycle.org.uk/publication/heldt_pnas_2018/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cell cycle transitions: a common role for stoichiometric inhibitors</title>
      <link>http://cellcycle.org.uk/publication/hopkins_mbcell_2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cellcycle.org.uk/publication/hopkins_mbcell_2017/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interlinked bistable mechanisms generate robust mitotic transitions</title>
      <link>http://cellcycle.org.uk/publication/novak_cellcycle_2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cellcycle.org.uk/publication/novak_cellcycle_2017/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NucliTrack: An integrated nuclei tracking application</title>
      <link>http://cellcycle.org.uk/publication/cooper_bioinformatics_2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cellcycle.org.uk/publication/cooper_bioinformatics_2017/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2017 Summer Project Meeting</title>
      <link>http://cellcycle.org.uk/news/2017_summer_meeting/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cellcycle.org.uk/news/2017_summer_meeting/</guid>
      <description>Our 2017 summer meeting was held on the 31st May at the University of Oxford, Department of Biochemistry, with a full day of talks and enthusiastic discussions from all the groups. Presentations were given by the investigators, post-docs and students and we were fortunate to have two members of the Scientific Advisory Board with us for the day, John Tyson (Virginia Polytechnic Institute, USA) and Valeriu Damian, Director of the Modelling and Translational Biology, GlaxoSmithKline.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>APC/C:Cdh1 Enables Removal of Shugoshin-2 from the Arms of Bivalent Chromosomes by Moderating Cyclin-Dependent Kinase Activity</title>
      <link>http://cellcycle.org.uk/publication/rattani_currbiol_2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cellcycle.org.uk/publication/rattani_currbiol_2017/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Science Week Interview with Professor Hochegger</title>
      <link>http://cellcycle.org.uk/news/march_2017_helfrid_video/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cellcycle.org.uk/news/march_2017_helfrid_video/</guid>
      <description>In a video to celebrate the 2017 British Science Week, Dr Helfrid Hochegger explains how his research investigates cell division and proliferation in the fight against cancer.
2017 British Science Week Video</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paper published in Nature Communications</title>
      <link>http://cellcycle.org.uk/news/2017_naturecomms_paper/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cellcycle.org.uk/news/2017_naturecomms_paper/</guid>
      <description>This paper details the discovery that a protein called p21 helps stop cells from passing on DNA damage that occurs during cell division. Since cancerous cells develop when genetic damage is left unchecked, the research could improve our understanding of what goes wrong in the lead-up to cancer. It could also help researchers develop new ways to kill off cancerous cells. The work published in the journal Nature Communications, found that high levels of p21 build up in cells that incur DNA damage as they divide.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DNA damage during S-phase mediates the proliferation-quiescence decision in the subsequent G1 via p21 expression</title>
      <link>http://cellcycle.org.uk/publication/barr_naturecommunications_2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cellcycle.org.uk/publication/barr_naturecommunications_2017/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Website</title>
      <link>http://cellcycle.org.uk/news/new_website_post/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cellcycle.org.uk/news/new_website_post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This week we launched our new website &lt;a href=&#34;http://cellcycle.org.uk/&#34;&gt;http://cellcycle.org.uk/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The site has been moved onto a more stable platform and the design adapted to fit in with the project team requirements. The publications section has been upgraded to display additional links, members’ pages now show their project publications and PPSIM Visualisation-Dashboard more easily accessible. The work was carried out by Lukas Hutter with support from Charlotte Smith. If you have any queries please contact Charlotte Smith at &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:charlotte.smith@bioch.ox.ac.uk&#34;&gt;charlotte.smith@bioch.ox.ac.uk&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>December 2016 Project Meeting</title>
      <link>http://cellcycle.org.uk/news/december_2016_project_meeting/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cellcycle.org.uk/news/december_2016_project_meeting/</guid>
      <description>Our annual project meeting was held in Keble College, Oxford and included two days of project updates, scientific presentations and sharing ideas. The presentations were divided into four sessions and all the groups joined in the animated discussions.
 BiCycle Project Meeting December 2016, Keble College, Oxford   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two Bistable Switches Govern M Phase Entry</title>
      <link>http://cellcycle.org.uk/publication/mochida_currbiol_2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cellcycle.org.uk/publication/mochida_currbiol_2016/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A PP2A-B55 recognition signal controls substrate dephosphorylation kinetics during mitotic exit</title>
      <link>http://cellcycle.org.uk/publication/cundell_jcb_2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cellcycle.org.uk/publication/cundell_jcb_2016/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interviews with Prof. Novak (in Hungarian)</title>
      <link>http://cellcycle.org.uk/news/june_2016_belainterview/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cellcycle.org.uk/news/june_2016_belainterview/</guid>
      <description>While on a visit to Budapest in May 2016, Bela Novak was interviewed for two Hungarian publications,. The interviews in Hungarian are available here.
Interview with the Budapest Science Meetup
Article in the Hungarian Chemical Journal</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bistability of mitotic entry and exit switches during open mitosis in mammalian cells</title>
      <link>http://cellcycle.org.uk/publication/hegarat_bioessays_2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cellcycle.org.uk/publication/hegarat_bioessays_2016/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nutritional Control of Cell Size by the Greatwall-Endosulfine-PP2A·B55 Pathway</title>
      <link>http://cellcycle.org.uk/publication/chica_currbiol_2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cellcycle.org.uk/publication/chica_currbiol_2016/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Dynamical Framework for the All-or-None G1/S Transition</title>
      <link>http://cellcycle.org.uk/publication/barr_cellsystems_2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cellcycle.org.uk/publication/barr_cellsystems_2016/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paper published in Cell Systems</title>
      <link>http://cellcycle.org.uk/news/2016_cellsystems_paper/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cellcycle.org.uk/news/2016_cellsystems_paper/</guid>
      <description>A major publication from the Bicycle project is helping to reveal how mammalian cells control transition into the DNA replication phase of the cell cycle. The research published in Cell Systems (1) comes from the ongoing collaboration between the labs of Bela Novak (Oxford) and Chris Bakal (ICR), who are investigators on the Bicycle project together with Francis Barr, Ulrike Gruneberg and Helfrid Hochegger. Postdocs Alexis Barr at the ICR and Stefan Heldt in Oxford are responsible for much of the work carried out for this paper.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Premature Sister Chromatid Separation Is Poorly Detected by the Spindle Assembly Checkpoint as a Result of System-Level Feedback</title>
      <link>http://cellcycle.org.uk/publication/mirkovic_cellreports_2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cellcycle.org.uk/publication/mirkovic_cellreports_2015/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Models in biology: lessons from modeling regulation of the eukaryotic cell cycle</title>
      <link>http://cellcycle.org.uk/publication/tyson_bmcbiology_2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cellcycle.org.uk/publication/tyson_bmcbiology_2015/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Model scenarios for switch-like mitotic transitions</title>
      <link>http://cellcycle.org.uk/publication/pk_febsletters_2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cellcycle.org.uk/publication/pk_febsletters_2015/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>December 2014 Project Meeting</title>
      <link>http://cellcycle.org.uk/news/december_2014_project_meeting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cellcycle.org.uk/news/december_2014_project_meeting/</guid>
      <description>Our first project meeting took place on the first official day of the grant, 1st December 2014. The meeting was held in the Department of Biochemistry in Oxford and involved all the project groups and representatives from project partner GSK.
 BiCycle Project Meeting December 2014, Biochemistry, Oxford   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code and Computational Resources</title>
      <link>http://cellcycle.org.uk/resource/code/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cellcycle.org.uk/resource/code/</guid>
      <description>Test, Test</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our Research</title>
      <link>http://cellcycle.org.uk/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cellcycle.org.uk/research/</guid>
      <description>Our Research During its growth and division cycle the cell replicates all of its components and distributes them to create two daughter cells [1]. It is essential that the underlying processes, DNA replication (S phase), mitosis (M phase) and cell division (CD), take place in a defined sequence with the correct temporal separation: G1 → S → G2 → M → CD → G1 → . Progression through this sequence is characterized by specific transitions at boundaries between sequential stages of the cell cycle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>alexis_barr</title>
      <link>http://cellcycle.org.uk/member/alexis_barr/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cellcycle.org.uk/member/alexis_barr/</guid>
      <description>Alexis Barr studied Biological Natural Sciences at the University of Cambridge, specialising in Biochemistry in her third and fourth years. She carried out her PhD in centrosome biology at the CRUK Cambridge Research Institute under the supervision of Fanni Gergely. During that time she used genetic engineering, molecular biology and live cell imaging to study centrosome function and microtubule dynamics during mitotic spindle assembly in vertebrate cells. In 2010, Alexis moved to the Institute of Cancer Research (ICR), London, to join Chris Bakal&amp;rsquo;s team for her Postdoctoral research, in order to take a systems-level approach to analyse the control of the G1/S transition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bela_novak</title>
      <link>http://cellcycle.org.uk/member/bela_novak/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cellcycle.org.uk/member/bela_novak/</guid>
      <description>Bela Novak trained as a biochemical engineer and started his research career as an experimental cell biologist working on the fission yeast cell cycle with Prof. Murdoch Mitchison. In the early nineties, in collaboration with Prof. John Tyson, he pioneered a systems-level description of eukaryotic cell cycle controls. The mathematical modelling approach that he established, based on biochemical reaction kinetics, computer simulations and dynamical systems theory, has proven effective in bridging the gap between molecular control networks and cell physiology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>charlotte_smith</title>
      <link>http://cellcycle.org.uk/member/charlotte_smith/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cellcycle.org.uk/member/charlotte_smith/</guid>
      <description>Charlotte Smith has worked for the University of Oxford since 2004. She has worked in finance and management roles at the Doctoral Training Centre and the Oxford Centre for Integrative Systems Biology (OCISB). Recently she has been working with departments across the Medical Sciences Division on Athena SWAN processes. For the Bistability of Cell Cycle Transitions project Charlotte works in a part-time project management role.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>chris_bakal</title>
      <link>http://cellcycle.org.uk/member/chris_bakal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cellcycle.org.uk/member/chris_bakal/</guid>
      <description>Chris Bakal’s contributions to biology have been to use imaging and computational methods to describe the signalling networks regulating cell shape. Specifically, the Bakal laboratory has developed the use of Quantitative Morphological Signatures (QMSs) to describe the contribution of individual genes to the regulation of single-cell shape (Bakal et al., Science 2007), automated online phenotype discovery algorithms that search through databases containing millions of images to identify novel cell shapes (Yin et al.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>code</title>
      <link>http://cellcycle.org.uk/code/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cellcycle.org.uk/code/</guid>
      <description>Test, Test</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>francis_barr</title>
      <link>http://cellcycle.org.uk/member/francis_barr/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cellcycle.org.uk/member/francis_barr/</guid>
      <description>Francis Barr is a cell biologist and biochemist working on the regulation of cell growth and division events. As a postdoctoral fellow with Graham Warren he identified new structural proteins of the Golgi apparatus that explain its profound structural rearrangements during the cell cycle. He has gone on to carry out ground-breaking studies on the role of Rab GTPases and their regulators in membrane trafficking. He demonstrated the function of Rab8 in primary cilium formation in human cells, and the molecular basis of altered membrane trafficking in human diseases including Hermansky Pudlak Syndrome, Geroderma Osteodyplastica, and Warburg Micro Syndrome.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>helfrid_hochegger</title>
      <link>http://cellcycle.org.uk/member/helfrid_hochegger/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cellcycle.org.uk/member/helfrid_hochegger/</guid>
      <description>Helfrid Hochegger works on cell cycle control using chemical genetic, advanced microscopy and proteomic approaches. He was trained in the Nobel Prize winning lab of Tim Hunt and has spent his career investigating the function of kinases and phosphatases in the regulation of cell cycle transitions. He distinguished himself by establishing a chemical genetics system to target mitotic and interphase Cdk activity in a vertebrate cell line. This work led to a prestigious Wellcome Trust career development award to set up a laboratory at the Genome Damage and Stability Centre at the University of Sussex.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>nadia_hegarat</title>
      <link>http://cellcycle.org.uk/member/nadia_hegarat/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cellcycle.org.uk/member/nadia_hegarat/</guid>
      <description>Nadia is interested in the link between cell cycle and genome stability. In cycling cells, the maintenance of genome integrity consists in faithful genome duplication, accurate segregation of the replicated chromosomes and repair of damaged DNA. She started her research career in France (“Régulation et dynamique des génomes”) where she developed a highly specific purification method of DNA repair complexes. In 2008, she joined Helfrid Hochegger’s group in the University of Sussex as a post-doctoral fellow to expand on her interest in cell cycle regulation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>scott_rata</title>
      <link>http://cellcycle.org.uk/member/scott_rata/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cellcycle.org.uk/member/scott_rata/</guid>
      <description>I am a fourth-year DPhil student, modelling the G2/M transition with Helfrid Hochegger&amp;rsquo;s group. We are investigating the factors that contribute to the triggering and to the hysteresis of this transtion.
My research interests also include the metaphase-to-anaphase transition, modelling the regulation of separase and its effects on the localisation of the chromosomal passenger complex.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>stefan_heldt</title>
      <link>http://cellcycle.org.uk/member/stefan_heldt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cellcycle.org.uk/member/stefan_heldt/</guid>
      <description>Stefan Heldt studied Biosystems Engineering at the Otto von Guericke University in Magdeburg, Germany. He received his degree in 2009 after completing a diploma thesis on stochastic simulations of mRNA translation in the group of Prof. Celso Grebogi at the University of Aberdeen, Scotland. He then joined the Max Planck Institute for Dynamics of Complex Technical Systems for a Ph.D. developing mechanistic, multi-scale models of influenza virus infection. This work awarded him the 2016 MTZ Award for Medical Systems Biology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ulrike_gruneberg</title>
      <link>http://cellcycle.org.uk/member/ulrike_gruneberg/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cellcycle.org.uk/member/ulrike_gruneberg/</guid>
      <description>Ulrike Gruneberg is a Senior Medical Research Fellow at the Sir William Dunn School of Pathology in Oxford. Ulrike received her postdoctoral training in the labs of Elmar Schiebel and Erich Nigg and was subsequently awarded a prestigious Cancer Research UK Career Development Fellowship to start her own lab, initially at the University of Liverpool and then at the University of Oxford. Ulrike’s lab studies the mechanisms that regulate spindle formation and chromosome segregation in mammalian cells.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>