<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Bakal on BBSRC Bistability of Cell Cycle Transitions Project</title>
    <link>http://cellcycle.org.uk/groups/bakal/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Bakal on BBSRC Bistability of Cell Cycle Transitions Project</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://cellcycle.org.uk/groups/bakal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Cyclin A Triggers Mitosis Either via the Greatwall Kinase Pathway or Cyclin B</title>
      <link>http://cellcycle.org.uk/publication/hegarat_emboj_2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cellcycle.org.uk/publication/hegarat_emboj_2020/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A comprehensive model for the proliferation-quiescence decision in response to endogenous DNA damage in human cells</title>
      <link>http://cellcycle.org.uk/publication/heldt_pnas_2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cellcycle.org.uk/publication/heldt_pnas_2018/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NucliTrack: An integrated nuclei tracking application</title>
      <link>http://cellcycle.org.uk/publication/cooper_bioinformatics_2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cellcycle.org.uk/publication/cooper_bioinformatics_2017/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DNA damage during S-phase mediates the proliferation-quiescence decision in the subsequent G1 via p21 expression</title>
      <link>http://cellcycle.org.uk/publication/barr_naturecommunications_2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cellcycle.org.uk/publication/barr_naturecommunications_2017/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Dynamical Framework for the All-or-None G1/S Transition</title>
      <link>http://cellcycle.org.uk/publication/barr_cellsystems_2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cellcycle.org.uk/publication/barr_cellsystems_2016/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>alexis_barr</title>
      <link>http://cellcycle.org.uk/member/alexis_barr/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cellcycle.org.uk/member/alexis_barr/</guid>
      <description>Alexis Barr studied Biological Natural Sciences at the University of Cambridge, specialising in Biochemistry in her third and fourth years. She carried out her PhD in centrosome biology at the CRUK Cambridge Research Institute under the supervision of Fanni Gergely. During that time she used genetic engineering, molecular biology and live cell imaging to study centrosome function and microtubule dynamics during mitotic spindle assembly in vertebrate cells. In 2010, Alexis moved to the Institute of Cancer Research (ICR), London, to join Chris Bakal&amp;rsquo;s team for her Postdoctoral research, in order to take a systems-level approach to analyse the control of the G1/S transition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>chris_bakal</title>
      <link>http://cellcycle.org.uk/member/chris_bakal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cellcycle.org.uk/member/chris_bakal/</guid>
      <description>Chris Bakal’s contributions to biology have been to use imaging and computational methods to describe the signalling networks regulating cell shape. Specifically, the Bakal laboratory has developed the use of Quantitative Morphological Signatures (QMSs) to describe the contribution of individual genes to the regulation of single-cell shape (Bakal et al., Science 2007), automated online phenotype discovery algorithms that search through databases containing millions of images to identify novel cell shapes (Yin et al.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>